本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 红鼻子的UFO 熊猫大虾 带着猫咪私奔 jojo108 Cinderella
校对： Cinderella    后期： 泡面小小
这城市正在自我毁灭 兄弟 所以我不愿参与
This city is eating itself, man. That's why I don't get involved.
- 我们达成交易了吗? - 成交
- Do we have a deal? - Whatever you need.
你的红毛搭档呢?
And your ang mo partner?
这是我们之间的交易
Let's just keep this between us.
那是詹姆斯・林没错
Well, that's James Lim, right.
他是个积极进取的生意人
He's a businessman on his way up,
他哥哥是林杰志 工会主要领袖
and his brother is Lim Chee Kit, the senior union leader.
我想和你一起看电影 能更了解你
I'd love to see a film with you, get to know you better.
为什么 你想给我立档案吗?
Why, so you can open a file on me?
听着 东南亚就像一个大型血腥跷跷板...
Listen, South-East Asia is like one big, bloody seesaw...
一边是美国中情局 另一边是英国军情六处
you have the CIA on one side, you've got MI6 on the other.
之前中情局特工先生来找过你
Mr CIA Agent was looking for you earlier.
- 忘记他吧 苏 - 你说话像我爸似的
- Forget him, Su. - You sound like my father.
你觉得他与众不同吗? 他不是
Why do you think he's different? He's not.
我想了想我说过的话 和相爱的人一起
I thought about what I said about being with people you love,
创造自己的生活
about making your own life.
我要离开弗兰克
I'm leaving Frank.
如果我没被录取怎么办?
What if I don't get in?
你没问题的
You will.
但我没接到任何消息
But I haven't heard anything.
别担心 没问题的 相信我
Don't worry. You will, trust me.
你会去纽约或华盛顿上学
You're going to go to school in New York or DC.
我会被调回兰利
I'm going to get posted back to Langley,
然后我可以带着你去看球赛
then I can take you to a ball game.
- 球赛? - 对 棒球 世上最棒的运动
- A ball game? - Yeah. Baseball. It's the greatest game in the world.
我能带你去谢亚球场看纽约大都会的比赛
I could take you to Shea Stadium to go and see the Mets.
那是我最爱的球队
That's my team.
他们去年输了差不多109场比赛
You know that last year they lost, like, 109 games.
- 太糟糕了吧 - 是啊 他们很差劲
- That's terrible. - It is. They were awful.
我肯定这会违背城市的法令 但...
I'm sure it's against a dozen city ordinances, but...
- 康拉德 - 怎么了?
- Conrad. - What is it?
在这等我一下
Just wait here for a minute.
你们在加班吗?
You guys working late?
老板想让我们把场地准备好 迎接早上的船员
Work site. Boss needs us to get it ready for the morning crew.
趴下 趴下!
Down, down!
你没事吧?
You OK?
在这等着警察来
Stay here. Wait for the police.
石龙岗之路 第一季第07集
窗帘
Mm, curtains.
窗帘怎么了?
Curtains?
我喜欢这里的窗帘 但要有点颜色才好
Yeah. I like it here, but it needs some colour.
来点自来水也许会好些
Some running water would help too.
很快就会有了
All in good time.
我们必须要这样吗?
Do we have to?
是的
Yes.
那弗兰克怎么办?
But what about Frank?
他这周末才回来
Well, he's not back till the weekend.
只有四天了
That's only four days.
我得亲口告诉他 这是他应得的
He needs to hear it from me. He deserves that.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
确定
Yes.
这就是我想要的 山姆
This is what I want, Sam.
这一切都是我想要的
It's all I want.
这是你想要的吗?
Is it what you want?
是的
Yeah.
你明天晚上有空吗 卡拉汉先生?
Are you free tomorrow night, Mr Callaghan?
康拉德没事吧?
Is Conrad alright?
- 你确定吗? - 只是有些割伤和瘀伤
- Are you sure? - Apart from some cuts and bruises.
大伙 看到这个了吗?
Guys, seen this?
时事日报的头条
Front page of The Chronicle.
目击证人... 陈苏玲小姐
'Eyewitness... Miss Ch'en Su Ling.'
这下可瞒不了你父母了
Just what your parents don't need to know.
等等 他们为什么指责林杰志教授?
Hang on, why are they blaming Professor Lim Chee Kit?
似乎爆炸案的幕后操手是工会
Seems like the union is behind the bombing.
但我认识林教授 这绝对不可能
But I know Professor Lim. That's impossible.
他只主张非暴力
He advocates nonviolence only.
是啊 非暴力炸弹
Yeah, nonviolent bombs.
他们炸毁了一个纹章 没人死亡
They blew up a coat of arms. Nobody died.
他们可能想说 看吧 独立就是个笑话
They might be trying to say, look, independence is a joke
我们还是在英国人的控制之下
and we're still under British control.
他们炸毁了一栋楼!
They blew up a building!
郑夫人
Mrs Cheng.
林先生 您怎么会下榻此地?
Mr Lim. To what do we owe the pleasure?
我哥哥和昨晚的爆炸案一点关系都没有
My brother had nothing to do with last night's bombing.
警察可不这么想
That's not what the cops think.
但是即使他们找到他 也不会逮捕他
But if they find him, they're not going to arrest him.
他们会杀了他 杀一儆百
They will make an example of Chee Kit, and they will kill him.
他们为何要怎么做?
Why would they do that?
你目击了昨晚的事
You saw what happened last night.
那个男人 没有武器 他们还是打死了他
The man, he was unarmed, and still they shot him.
特务处和政府觉得
Well, Special Branch and the government
齐基特是政治威胁
see Chee Kit as a political threat.
我们能为你做什么?
What can we do for you?
我想带齐基特去海外
I want to take Chee Kit offshore.
国内安全法规定
Internal Security Act.
要是警察抓到我们带危险分子离开岛内...
The cops catch us taking a subversive off the island...
..那就要去樟宜坐牢了
..it's a long holiday in Changi.
我不是让你带他走 只是找到他就好
I'm not asking you to take him, just find him.
等风头过了 我会自己安排船
And when it's safe, I'll arrange a boat myself.
你有很多关系网 为什么你不自己找?
You're well connected. Why can't you find him?
我想他不会想见我 但...
I don't think he would want me to, but...
..毕竟他是我哥哥
..he's my brother.
为什么詹姆斯・林想让他哥哥离开岛内?
Why would James Lim want to get his brother off the island?
齐基特很有社会正义感...
Chee Kit is Mr Social Justice...
是为马来西亚着想的马来西亚人
Malaysians for Malaysia and all that.
詹姆士不介意红毛吗?
And James doesn't mind the ang mo?
只要他能从我们这获利
As long as he can make money off us.
詹姆士有野心 政治野心
The word is, James has ambitions, political ambitions.
或许这就是他希望他哥哥离开的原因
Maybe that's why he wants his brother gone.
安格 我要一杯祭奠酒
Ange, I need a libation.
我刚给过你一杯
I just poured you one.
我还能说什么呢? 我喜欢你的服务
Well, what can I say? I love the service.
天哪 迈卡
Jesus, Macca.
你认识山姆・卡拉汉吗?
Have you met Sam Callaghan?
没 但我听说过你 你是个调查员
No, but I've heard about you. You're the investigator.
安格・沃诺克 很高兴见到你
Ange Warnock. Pleased to meet you.
- 你好 - 我们得谈谈
- Yeah, g'day. - We have to talk.
我听说在中国城你有很多熟人
I hear you have contacts in Chinatown.
是吗? 谁告诉你的?
Yeah? Who told you that?
你随时可以来找我
You can always talk to me, you know.
瞧 谁来了
Mm. Look who's here.
你允许我加入了吗?
You going to fill me in?
毫无疑问
Absolutely.
想当记者
Wannabe journalist.
她很有才
She's good.
如果她老跟你聊 可成不了才
She won't be if she talks to you.
阿姆兰探长 对昨晚的枪击案有何看法?
Inspector Amran. Any comments on the shooting last night?
去和公共联络组谈吧
Go speak to the Public Liaison Unit.
你的朋友康在哪里?
Where's your friend Kang?
为什么问他? 他做了什么?
Why, what's he done?
他是我们昨晚击毙的恐怖分子的已知同谋
He's a known associate of the terrorist we shot last night.
已知同谋? 嘿 那是啥意思?
A 'known associate'. Hey, what's that mean?
告诉你朋友 只要他能来自首
Tell your friend it will be safer for everyone
这样对大家都好
if he comes in on his own accord.
别太生气
Don't get too pissed.
当然不会
Of course not.
你昨晚被兰利的人盯上了
You got noticed last night at Langley.
我被打晕了就引起他们关注了?
Getting knocked out got me noticed?
手无寸铁去抓恐怖分子 勇气可嘉 他们喜欢
Unarmed, chasing terrorists. Shows mettle. They like that.
炸弹袭击引起了他们的警戒
The bomb attack got their attention.
兰利的人想摸清楚新加坡每个人的底细
Langley wants a who's-who in the Singapore zoo
跟齐基特合作的工会活动家
union activists who work with Chee Kit,
共产党拥护者 以及间谍
communist sympathisers, spies.
你懂的
You know the drill.
所有不该拿到美国签证的人都需要调查
Pretty much anyone who shouldn't get a US visa.
看你的了
It's all yours.
这是什么?
What is this?
兰利的人说服军情六处跟我们共享情报
Langley convinced MI6 to share their intelligence with us.
米勒上校同意了?
And Major Miller agreed?
他跟我们一样担心共产主义分子啊
He's as worried about the commies as we are.
玩得开心哦
Have fun.
三小时前你就该在这了
You were supposed to be here three hours ago.
- 警察在找你 - 所以呢?
- The cops are looking for you. - So?
阿姆兰说你认识昨晚被打死的那个人
Amran says you knew the guy they shot last night,
就是那个带炸弹的人
the guy with the bomb.
没错 他叫炎 在码头工作
Yeah. His name is Yam. He works on the wharfs.
你也认识他 他不大爱讲话
You knew him too. He doesn't really talk to anybody.
- 你没帮工会跑过运输吧? - 没有
- You haven't done any transports for the unions, have you? - No.
- 康? - 我说了没有!
- Kang? - I said no!
他们已经在监视你了
They've got their eye on you.
答应我别再做傻事了
Promise me you won't do anything stupid.
好吧 随便啦
Yeah, whatever.
也许你也应该言而有信吧
Maybe you should start keeping your promises too.
这话什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
别装蒜 你自己清楚
You know exactly what it means.
你可以告诉辛普森太太 新加坡地方很小
And you can tell Mrs Simpson that Singapore is very small.
你做了什么事 大家都看得见
When someone sees something, everybody sees it.
我带着很多梦想来到这里
I came here with such high hopes,
我不会错过任何一个的
but I won't miss any of this.
你不会要去哪吧?
You're not going anywhere, are you?
不会
No.
别告诉我弗兰克被调走了
Oh, don't tell me Frank's been transferred?
什么? 没 他没跟我说过
What? No, no, no. Not that he's told me.
- 我记得你说过他周末才回来 - 没错
- I thought you said he was away till the weekend. - Mm. He is.
好啊...
Well...
亲爱的!
Darling!
- 弗兰克 - 塔克沃思女士
- Frank. - Lady Tuckworth.
我以为你周日才回来呢
I thought you weren't back till Sunday.
好消息是 我们提前几天把合同签定了
The good news is, we got the deal signed off a few days early.
坏消息是 我马上又要
The bad news is, I'm on a ferry to Batam
坐船去班特姆
in less time than it takes to get there.
- 我很想跟你说些事情 - 抱歉
- I really need to talk to you. - I'm sorry.
我明晚回来 下周一休息
I'll be back tomorrow night. I'll take Monday off.
- 整个周末我们都会在一起 - 弗兰克
- We'll have a whole long weekend together... - Frank.
...八点在这吃晚饭 好吗?
...starting with dinner right here at eight o'clock, OK?
我爱你
I love you.
再见塔克沃思女士
Lady Tuckworth.
费利克斯现在是纺织协会的会计
Felix is now an accountant for a textile union.
他能带我们去找到齐基特?
And he can get us to Chee Kit?
没错 他自己说的
Yes, that's what he says.
我们大学的时候一起上过林教授的课
We were both in Professor Lim's class at university.
你俩都是激进派的学生么?
Were you both student radicals?
我们不是激进分子
We weren't radicals.
我们被卷入了一次学校的政治抗议活动
We were involved in a political school protest.
那是很久之前的事情了
And that's history.
你跟费利克斯约会多久了?
How long did you go out with Felix?
我没有啊 他父母曾经觉得我们很般配
I didn't. His parents just once thought we might be a good match.
- 那你跟他分手了吗? - 没有啊
- So you broke up with him? - No.
有一点吧 已经很久之前了
Well, maybe a little, but it was such a long time ago,
他很开心我今天来看他
and he was quite happy for me to come see him today.
你跟他说过你在中情局的童子军经历么?
Did you tell him about your CIA boy scout?
哈里森先生不是童子军
Mr Harrison is not a boy scout.
你没跟他说过 对吧?
You didn't tell him, did you?
我在帮你和费利克斯重归于好
I'm going to try and get you and Felix back together.
他是会计 听起来像个顽固的家伙
He's an accountant. Sounds like a solid chap.
山姆 你怎么了? 怎么这么开心?
Sam, what's wrong with you? Why are you happy?
有吗? 我怎么没注意到
Am I? I hadn't noticed.
你肯定是发烧了
It's got to be a fever.
我应该取消这次见面
I should call this meeting off.
- 别说话 - 怎么了?
- Stop talking. - What's the matter?
没什么 别停
Nothing. Keep walking.
我们被跟踪了吗?
Are we being followed?
我估计是 只是想确定一下
I think so. I just want to make sure.
谁会跟踪我们?
Who would follow us?
不知道 警察 政治保安部的人
I don't know. Police, Special Branch.
我来支走他们 你去跟费利克斯见面
I'll distract them, you meet up with Felix.
- 什么? 山姆! - 快走
- What? Sam! - Go, go.
你好
Hi.
Hello.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
我听说你和郑太太跟外国人一起工作
I heard that you and Mrs Cheng are working with an ang mo.
这个叫山姆・卡拉汉的人
This Sam Callaghan,
他可能是英国或者美国的间谍
he could be spying for the British or the Americans.
不会的 山姆是澳洲人 他不是间谍 我保证
No, Sam's Australian, and he's not a spy, I promise.
帮帮我
你现在已经变成大美女了
You've become a very beautiful woman.
我早就知道你是个美女
I always knew you would.
费利克斯 你真知道林博士藏在哪里吗?
Felix, do you really know where Professor Lim is hiding?
没错
Yes.
我们跟你一样不想让警察参和进来
We don't want the police involved any more than you do,
但是詹姆斯・林说他很担心
but James Lim says he's worried,
所以我只是想代表他跟林博士说几句
so I just want to speak to Professor Lim for him.
拜托了
Please.
好的 在这等着 我跟他打个电话
OK. Stay here. I'll give him a call.
谢谢
Thank you.
有什么新发现?
Anything interesting?
- 哈里森 - 米勒上校
- Harrison. - Major Miller.
- 没什么发现 - 没找出是谁?
- Uh, no. - No names stand out?
还没 我只是...
No. No, not yet. I just...
我是说 大部分情报信息都是五年十年前的了
I mean, most of this intelligence is five, ten years old.
你想让我安排戴维斯
You want me to get Davies
- 来跟你一起工作吗? - 不用
- to go over the rest of it with you? - No.
我已经着手在办了
I've started.
他只是坐在这里无所事事
He's just sitting out there swatting flies.
我会让他开工的 没理由浪费你的时间
I'll get him off his butt. No reason to waste your time.
不会的 再花几个小时就行了
No, it's only going to take me a couple more hours.
- 真的么? - 是的
- You sure? - Yeah, yeah.
奉献精神 我喜欢
Dedication. I like that.
现在 我要跟米勒上校一起午餐
Me, right now, I'm dedicated to lunch with Major Miller.
如果你想的话 搞完之后来俱乐部见我们
Meet us in the club when you're done, if you want.
好的 谢谢
OK. Thanks.
这辆
This one.
抱歉... 你得进后备箱
Sorry... you've got to go into the boot.
这边请
This way.
陈苏玲
Ch'en Su Ling.
林教授 好久不见 见到你很高兴
Professor Lim. Good to see you.
我也是
And you.
费利克斯告诉我是我弟弟让你来的
Felix tells me my brother sent you.
是的
Yes.
他担心警察会抓到你
He was worried that the police might catch you.
现在詹姆士唯一担心的 像他自己说的
The only thing that ever worried James, as he calls himself now,
就是银行余额
is his bank balance.
他想让我离开这里 不是吗?
He wants me to leave the country, doesn't he?
他说他不想让你死或者去樟宜坐牢
He said he didn't want you dead or in Changi.
如果我走了 就不能为我的人民做事了
If I leave, I can't do anything for my people.
所以请告诉他你找到我了
So please, tell him you have found me,
我会谢谢他的关心
and I thank him for his concern,
但是我会继续呆在新加坡
but I will stay here in Singapore.
但是 林教授 有人昨天被杀了
But, Professor Lim, a man was killed yesterday.
请让我们保护你
Please let us help protect you.
再次看见你真好
It was good to see you again.
对不起 我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
为什么我们在这里见面?
Why are we meeting here anyway?
康拉德 怎么了?
Conrad, what's the matter?
你说过我们认识以前
You said that before we met
你就是个梳马尾辫的姑娘
you were just a pigtailed girl.
你希望地方自治 民主 如此而已
You wanted home rule,democracy . That's all.
是这样的 怎么了?
Yeah, that's true. Why?
我发现一篇有关你的情报
I found an intelligence report on you.
- 是六年前的 是罪证 - 这不可能
- It's from six years ago, but it's incriminating.- Oh, it can't be.
我看完了整个文件 确定只有一份
I went through the rest of the files, made sure there was only one.
上面说什么?
What does it say?
说你曾经组织学生抗议
It says that you used to organise student protests
而你就是...
and that you were a...
...共产党的支持者
..communist sympathiser.
你怎么能信这个呢?
How can you believe that?
这是真的吗?
Is that true?
我 陈苏玲 庄严地发誓我不是共产党的人
I, Ch'en Su Ling, solemnly swear that I am not,
现在不是 从前也不是
nor have I ever been, a member of the Communist Party.
这不是玩笑
This is not a joke.
谁写的报告?
Who wrote the report?
不知道 从来没听说过他
I don't know. Never heard of him.
是个叫费利克斯・姚的人
It's a guy named Felix Yao.
- 姚? - 姚
- Yao? - Yao
对 你认识他吗?
Yeah. Do you know him?
- 是的 - 你上次见他是什么时候?
- Yes. - When was the last time you saw him?
- 今天 - 今天? 为什么?
- Today. - Today? Why?
为了郑夫人 这一定有什么误会
For Mrs Cheng. There's got to be a mistake.
我已经好几年没见过他了
I hadn't seen him in years,
但是他绝对不会这样诽谤我
but he would never say these things about me.
他六年前死了
Well, six years ago he did,
如果这些文件泄漏了
and if this file ever gets out,
你将永远不会得到美国签证
you will never get a US visa.
但是康拉德 为什么他要给我造谣?
But Conrad, why would he lie about me?
我不知道
I don't know.
他为什么要这样?
Why would he?
不要跑 我们是警察 站住别跑!
我们是警察 站住别跑!
好吧! 好了
OK, OK, OK! Alright.
警官 不要再开了啦 警官
你们要的话我送你们一盒
这个是特别高级的
特别高级
Extra special.
这是什么?
警官我什么都不知道
这不是我的 OK?
这不是我的 不是我的
你要相信我 这不是我的
警官
山姆 我是被陷害的
Sam, I was set up.
爆炸后的一天 警察搜查了整个海港
The day after the bombing, cops crawling all over the harbour,
- 你却走私炸药? - 不 我没有
- and you smuggle in C-4? - No, I didn't.
- 我没警告过你吗? - 先听我说行吗?
- Didn't I warn you? - Would you just listen to me?
不管他们给我多少钱
No matter how much money they offer me,
你认为我会傻到携带炸药?
do you actually think I'm that stupid, to bring in C-4?
你真认为我这么傻吗?
Do you really think I'm that stupid?
阿姆兰认为你是
Amran thinks you are.
那个人总是看我不顺眼
That guy always had something against me.
好吧 那你怎么处理这件事
Well, what are we going to do about it?
你知道被指控走私罪会怎么样
You know what the charge is for a smuggling offence.
他们会杀了你
They're going to hang you.
所以说你得相信我 山姆
That's why you have to believe me, Sam.
你得相信我 我是被陷害的
You have to believe me. I was set up.
好 我相信你
Yeah, I believe you.
我不就是把你弄出来吗
My opinion isn't going to get you out of here.
- 谁雇的你? - 就是有一批亚力酒的人
- Who hired you? - Just some guy with a shipment of arak.
- 你现在还想着保护他? - 我不是
- You're going to protect him now? - I'm not pro...
好吧 你肯定不想听到这些
Fine. You're not going to like this.
我不知道是谁 但我知道我为什么被陷害
I don't know who, but I think I know why I was set up.
我曾经给工会运过亚力酒
I have been transporting arak for the unions.
爆炸以后 即使知道阿姆兰在找你?
After the bombing, knowing Amran is looking for you?
这只是份工作 好吧?
It was just a job, OK?
我就是在赚钱 把亚力酒带到工会俱乐部
I was making money, bringing in arak for union clubs.
就这么多 就这样 好吧?
That's all. That was it, OK?
没有枪支 没有爆炸物 没那回事 山姆
No guns, no explosives, nothing like that, Sam.
我发誓 我发誓 我是被陷害的
I swear  I swear, man I was set up.
好吧
Alright.
你认为是我的人把炸药放到船上的?
You think my men planted C-4 on his boat?
- 我是说 他是被陷害的 - 被谁?
- That's not what I'm saying, but he was set up.- By who?
我不知道 他曾经为工会走私亚力酒 就这样
I don't know. He was smuggling arak for the unions. That's it.
别这样 你知道康
Oh, come on. You know Kang.
他就会投机取巧 不过不是激进分子
He's an opportunist, but he's not an activist.
他不会走私炸药的
He's not going to smuggle C-4.
- 你现在找到什么吗? - 还没有
- Have you found anything yet? - Not yet.
好吧 你们根本找不到
Well, you're not going to.
我们会继续搜查
We'll keep searching.
我们要扣押你的船 直到康被审判
And... we're impounding your boat until Kang's trial.
等一下 等一下
Oh, hang on, hang on.
你甚至没有考虑过康可能是被陷害的吗?
You're not even going to consider the possibility that Kang was set up?
如果你错了 他要被吊死
If you're wrong, he'll hang.
我来告诉你我考虑的是什么
I'll tell you what I'll consider.
带林杰志来见我
Bring me Lim Chee Kit,
我可能会把你朋友往积极的方面想
I may take a favourable view towards your friend.
你认为齐基特计划了爆炸事件?
You think Chee Kit planted the explosives?
我不知道 但你把他带来的时候我会考虑
I don't know, but I'll consider that when you bring him to me.
为什么 所以你要带他去见警察?
Why, so you can take him to the police?
不 我只是想和他说话
No, I just want to talk to him.
你认为他是无辜的 是吗?
You think he's guilty, don't you?
我不知道 我想找到谁该对爆炸事件负责
I don't know. I want to find out who's responsible for the bombing.
- 我说了 不是林教授 - 你又不知道
- I told you. It's not Professor Lim. - But you don't know that.
但我知道如果找不到谁在他船上藏了爆炸物
But I know Kang will hang
康会被吊死
if we can't find out who planted explosive on his boat.
你想看他被吊死吗?
Do you want to see him hang?
对不起 我无能为力
Sorry. There's nothing I can do.
- 不许动 - 你想干什么?
- Don't move. - What do you want from me?
- 你是谁? - 你不会想知道的
- Who are you? - You don't want to know.
我没做错任何事情
I've done nothing wrong.
不许动 这不对 费利克斯
Don't move. That's not true, Felix.
别看我
Don't look at me.
这是你的签名吗?
Is that your signature?
- 你从哪得到的? - 这是你的签名吗?
- Where did you get it from? - Is that your signature?
是
Yes.
现在 你指控陈苏...
Now, you accused Ch'en Su...
别看我!
Don't look at me!
你指控 陈苏玲是共产党的支持者
You accused Ch'en Su Ling of being a communist sympathiser.
- 是真的吗? - 不!
- Is that true? - No!
那你为什么要撒谎 费利克斯?
Then why did you lie, Felix?
我很生气
I was angry.
我的父母...
My parents...
...他们以为我们会很合适
..they thought that we'd be a good match together,
但是她对我没有兴趣
but she just wasn't interested in me.
所以你做了一个假报告 是吗? 是不是?
So you made a false report, did you? Did you?
我会撤回那个
I'll retract it.
我会告诉他们我撒谎了闭嘴 闭嘴
I'll tell them I lied. Shut up, shut up.
接下来 你什么也不要说
This is what you're going to do. You're going to say nothing.
如果有任何人问起你那上面有什么
If anyone ever asks you what was in that,
你就否认你交过它 明白了吗?
you're going to deny you ever gave it, is that understood?
是的 我什么也不说
Yes. I will say anything.
如果我再听到你说陈苏玲任何消息
If I ever hear of you giving information on Ch'en Su Ling again
我会再来这 我知道你住在哪
I will come back here. I know where you live.
现在 站起来 面向墙 别看着我
Now, get up, face the wall. Don't look at me.
别看我 面向墙
Don't look at me. Face the wall.
数到五十
Count to 50.
好的
OK.
肯定是工会的人指使的阿拉克
It must have been one of the union guys that ordered the arak.
在找到你之前就已经装好了
It would have been loaded in before it got to you.
我猜是的
Yeah, I guess.
但是我说了 我认不出来他们
But I told you  I can't identify any of them.
我们要找出齐基特
We've got to find Chee Kit.
也许他知道些什么
Maybe he knows something.
如果是齐基特干的呢?
What if it WAS Chee Kit?
我会把他带来
I'll bring him in.
投弹手就交给你了 这是和阿姆兰的交易
The bomber for you. That was the deal with Amran.
你知道我上哪能找到他吗?
Do you know where I can find him?
康?
Kang?
我不知道他住在哪...
I don't know where he lives...
...但我知道他在哪祷告
...but I do know where he prays.
别再跟踪我了 任务结束了
Stop tailing me. The job's finished.
你的兄弟不相信你不是我们的错
It's not our fault your brother doesn't trust you.
他知道你和阿姆兰探员之间的交易吗?
Does he know about your deal with Inspector Amran?
我在警察局有很多人脉
I have many sources in the police department,
我会毫不犹豫的利用他们
and I wouldn't hesitate to use them
来保护我哥哥
to protect my brother.
不好意思
新加坡的大街上已经有
Already there's too much violence
太多暴力事件了
on the streets of Singapore.
我们的组织对这些事没有采取任何措施
Our union has never resorted to such things.
时代在改变
我们不应该继续被外国人欺压
这件事是应该被表扬的
- 是我吩咐的 - 你应该!
我们的人民已经厌倦了等待！
那是一次错误
唯一的错误是
炸药不够
我们的目标应该是内阁会议
不! 如果我们杀掉政府官员
No! If we kill government officials,
那么就不会再有人支持我们了
there will be no support among the people.
- 那就把他们都干掉 - 不!
- Then we'll take them all out. - No!
每个炸弹都会让英国人
Every bomb is another excuse
有理由把军队留下来
for the British to leave their troops here.
只要我还是工会的领头人
While I am the leader of this union,
我们就不能使用暴力
we will not use violence.
警察 举手站起来!
不! 不能用枪
No! No guns.
不能用枪!
No guns!
如果你不想死
跟我来
- 你是谁? - 苏玲的朋友
- Who are you? - A friend of Su Ling's.
你别无选择
You've got no choice.
这边
This way.
你为什么要帮我?
Why are you helping me?
我不想和我哥哥有任何关系
I don't want anything to do with my brother.
我不为你哥哥工作
I don't work for your brother.
我这么做是为了小康 - 康?
I'm doing this for Xiao Kang. - Kang?
他是我的朋友 他被陷害了 现在在监狱
He's a friend of mine. He's in prison for something he didn't do.
警察为什么抓他?
What do the police think he did?
他们认为他为你们工会走私炸药
They think he smuggled explosives for your union.
他们是对的
They're right.
等等 等等!
Wait. Wait!
我说了 等下! 你说什么 康做了什么?
I said, wait! What are you talking about, what did Kang do?
你想听实话?
You want the truth?
康为高和那些好战分子走私炸药
Kang smuggled weapons for Gao and the militant ones.
不 不 不 不 他没有
No. No, no. No, he didn't.
但他和邮局的事没有关系
But he had nothing to do with the post office.
那都是高义做的
That was all Gao Yi.
我劝过他 但是...
I tried to get him to stop but...
救我
Help me.
坚持下 叫救护车!
Hang in there. Get an ambulance!
快点 叫救护车!
Quickly, get an ambulance!
齐基特没有命令袭击邮局
Chee Kit didn't order the attack on the post office.
谁命令的?
Who did?
他说应该是高义
He said it could have been Gao Yi.
你看到是谁开枪打的他吗?
Did you see who shot him?
嘿 山姆... 我有个主意
Hey, Sam... I've got an idea.
叔叔? 如果我想找个医生来取出子弹
Uncle? If I was looking for a doctor to take out a bullet,
不能问问题 我该去哪?
no questions asked, where would I go?
不能找医生啊
为什么?
他们会报警
我带你去找后门的医生
见到这个很惊讶吗?
Surprised to see that?
我不知道这是什么
I don't know what it is.
这需要点说服力 但是那个后门医生
It took some persuading, but that backstreet doctor
已经承认是他从彭立的肩膀取出这颗子弹的
admitted that he pulled it out of Peng Li's shoulder.
- 彭立 我的手下? - 是的
- Peng Li who works for me? - That's right.
他今晚没来上班
He didn't show up to work tonight.
我想知道发生了什么事
I wondered what had happened.
你哥哥可能要死了
Your brother is probably going to die.
他能告诉警察什么 让你这么害怕?
What is it you're so scared that he could possibly tell the police?
我听说你当时在那
I heard you were there.
在我哥哥中枪之前他说什么了吗?
Did my brother say anything before you let him get shot?
总有一天你会后悔这么说的
You're going to regret saying that one day.
你不会想成为我的敌人的 卡拉汉先生
You don't want me to be an enemy, Mr Callaghan.
现在说这个有点晚了
It's a bit late for that.
如果你的人跟踪警察...
If your man followed the cops...
...他们怎么知道我在哪的?
...how the hell did they know where I was?
交易就是交易 对吧?
A deal's a deal, huh?
他们抓到投弹手然后放我走了
They caught the bomber and they let me go.
我欠你个人情 伙计 谢谢
I owe you one, man. Thanks.
那么... 齐基特还能活命吗?
So is... Chee Kit going to live?
你还关心这个? 是你告诉警察他在哪的
What do you care? You told the police where he was.
你为什么不等等? 我会把他活着弄出来的
Why didn't you wait? I would have got him out alive.
我别无选择 伙计 他们已经知道...
I didn't have a choice, man. They already knew...
你一直都有选择
You've always got a choice.
警察欠你的 康 他们欠你的!
The police own you, Kang. They own you!
听着 我当初就告诉你了 不是我没说
Look, I told you about this first. It's not like I didn't tell you.
至少和你在这 我觉得 你知道
At least with you there, I thought, you know,
齐基特还有机会出来
Chee Kit could have a chance that he could get out.
我知道他和邮局的事无关
I knew he had nothing to do with the post office.
为什么我要相信你?
Why should I believe you?
你陷害我 你欺骗我工会的事
You set me up, you lied about the unions,
欺骗我走私的事 欺骗我关于齐基特的事
you lied about the smuggling, you lied about Chee Kit.
- 你陷害我 康! - 他们要杀了我!
- You set me up, Kang! - They were going to hang me!
我早就知道你是在装无辜
I always knew you'd play an angle.
这对我来说没什么
I didn't have a problem with that.
但我从来... 从来没想到你会这样欺骗我
But I never... I never thought you'd lie to me like that.
他可能就要死了
He's probably going to die.
我们结束了
We're done.
我们早就结束了 山姆
We've been done for a while, Sam.
你好啊 亲爱的
Hello, darling.
你看起来 跟平常一样漂亮
You look beautiful, as usual.
我们可以走了吗?
Shall we?
我... 我觉得我们该回去
I... I think we should go.
听着 对不起 克莱尔
Look, I'm so sorry, Claire.
我知道 过去这六个月 我几乎每周末都出差
I know, these last six months, I've been gone nearly every weekend.
- 弗兰克... - 不 请你让我说完
- Frank... - No, let me finish, please.
我跟麦斯威尔谈过了
I've spoken to Maxwell.
他也同意我一直在干着三个人的活儿
He agrees I've been doing the job of three men.
所以 他会给我请个助手
So, he's getting me an assistant
还给我一个周的假期
and giving me a two-week vacation
从今晚开始
starting tonight.
你想去哪里我们就去哪里...
We can go anywhere you want...
意大利 澳大利亚 美国
Italy, Australia, the US.
随便说
You name it.
我哪里也不想去
I don't want to go anywhere.
那我们就待在这儿 放松一下 睡个懒觉
Then we can stay here. Relax, sleep late.
- 随便你想干什么 - 弗兰克...
- Whatever you want to do. - Frank...
...我真的觉得我们该回家
...I really think we should go home.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
听着 我不想在这里说 我觉得我们该回家
Look, I don't want to do this here. I think we should go home.
说什么? 怎么了?
Do what here? What is it?
克莱尔?
Claire?
弗兰克 我喜欢上了别人 我要搬走了
Frank, I've met someone. I'm moving out.
谁?
Who?
弗兰克...
Frank...
- 是谁? - 嘘!
- Who is it? - Shh!
我想喊就喊
I'll shout if I want to.
是谁 克莱尔?
Who is it, Claire?
山姆・卡拉汉
Sam Callaghan.
- 你开玩笑吧 - 我不是有意这样的
- You're kidding me. - I didn't plan on any of this.
你喜欢他多久了?
How long have you been seeing him?
- 弗兰克 - 多久?
- Frank. - How long?
有几个月了
A couple of months.
这么说你要搬去跟山姆・卡拉汉一起住了
So you're going to move in with Sam Callaghan.
你以为这样会持久吗?
You think that will last?
是的 我相信
I do, yes.
- 对不起 - 够了
- I'm so sorry. - Enough.
你走吧
Just go.
我回家收拾一下东西
I'm going to have to pick up a few things from home.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
明天早上我会离开的 到时候你可以过来收拾
I'll make sure I'm gone tomorrow. You can pick them up then.
# 任何人 #
Anyone
# 你可以责怪我 #
You can blame me
# 或者来羞辱我 #
Try to shame me
# 我仍然在乎你 #
And still I'll care for you
# 你可以四处游荡 #
You can run around
# 甚至把我辜负 #
Even put me down
# 世人也许笑我痴傻 #
The world may think I'm foolish
# 他们无法看见 #
They can't see you
# 我眼中的你 #
Like I can
# 不过任何人 #
Oh, but anyone
# 任何懂得爱的人 #
Who knows what love is
# 终会明白 #
Will understand
# 任何人 #
Anyone
# 任何人 我只是为那些同情我的人#
Anyone I just feel so sorry
# 任何人 觉得抱歉 #
Anyone For the ones who pity me...?
辛普森夫人
Mrs Simpson.
我想见山姆 不过他还没回来
I was supposed to meet Sam, but he hasn't come back yet.
恐怕我帮不了你
I'm afraid I can't help you.
拜托 他说他会在这里的
Please. He said he'd be here.
稍等一下
Give me a moment.
康!
Kang!
郑夫人?
Mrs Cheng?
我们找不到山姆
他在这里吗?
不在
你知道他在哪里吗?
你确定想看到这些吗?
Are you sure you want to see this?
他... 他还好吗?
Is... is he alright?
还好
Yeah.
几个小时之内他哪里都不能去
He won't be going anywhere for a few hours.
最好让他睡一会儿
Better to just let him sleep it off here.
不用担心 我早上会带他回家的
Don't worry. I'll bring him home in the morning.
我被录取了 哥伦比亚和乔治城
I got in. Columbia and Georgetown,
纽约和华盛顿 被你说中了
New York and Washington DC, just like you said.
太棒了
That's great.
康拉德 怎么了?
Conrad, what's the matter?
我销毁了你的文档
I destroyed your file.
我跟你的朋友费利克斯聊了聊
I had a chat to your buddy Felix.
我觉得他不会再找你麻烦了
I don't think that he'll bother you anymore.
- 你做了什么? - 没什么
- What did you do? - Nothing.
我们只是... 聊了聊
We just... had a little talk.
但是从现在开始你必须低调行事
But I need you to stay under the radar from now on.
- 康拉德 看 雷达呢 - 苏玲...
- Conrad, look radar. - Su Ling...
好吧 我什么也不干
OK. Yes, I'm not doing anything.
不准聚会 不准跟你的朋友们谈论美国什么的
No rallies. No talking to your friends about the US or anything.
都不准
Nothing.
要多久?
For how long?
只要你还想要签证就得这样
For as long as you want a visa.
我把文件销毁了
I got rid of the file,
但我不确定他们只有那一份材料
but I can't be certain that's the only one they have.
要是他们发现你有这么一段前科还在制造麻烦
If they find out you've got a history and see you making trouble
还跟人们谈论越南的事
and talking to people about Vietnam or anything,
他们就会撤回你的签证并且把你遣回家
they will revoke your visa and they will send you home.
- 不 他们不能这样 - 不 他们能
- No, they can't do that. - Yes, they can do that.
因为有前科的人是不能得到学习签证的
Because people with histories don't get study visas.
我要你向我保证
I need you to promise me
从现在开始你会保持低调
that you will stay under the radar from now on.
我保证 都听你的
I promise. Whatever you say.
哈里森先生
Mr Harrison.
我能跟你说两句吗?
Can we have a word?
恐怕要单独谈谈
Alone, I'm afraid.
女孩子很漂亮呢
Pretty girl.
你想让我找到她的档案
You wanted me to find her file.
所以你才给我们情报
That's why you gave us the intelligence.
别担心 这些只有这么多了
Don't worry. These go no further than here.
我们有很多有意思的照片
We have many interesting photographs.
听说你搞丢了一些澳大利亚女孩
Heard you lost a couple of Australian girls.
她们没上船
The girls weren't on the ship when it docked
并且在新加坡乘客没有登陆记录
and Customs has no record of disembarkation in Singapore.
要不他们会杀了她们
拢10,000 or they'll kill 'em.
谁控制岸边这一带?
Who controls the waterfront?
凯・索和他的团伙
Kay Song and his thugs.
"格雷齐尔的女儿相当恐怖"
'Grazier's Daughter Triad Horror.'
这故事里面说的
The story writes itself.
你应该感激我没有即刻杀了你
You should be grateful I don't kill you where you stand.
你是我和兰利的新纽带
You're my new conduit into Langley.
你想让我为你监视中情局?
You want me to spy on the CIA for you?
- 我看见你丈夫了 - 你看见?
- I saw your husband... - Did you see...?
就在他死的那晚
...on the night he died.
你知道是怎么回事吗?
Do you know what happened?
振作点 你现在是一名真正的间谍了
Chin up. You're a real spy now.